A Guide to the Mary Josephine King Papers, 1918-2003
Library of Virginia
- Series II: Genealogical Correspondence., Extent: 5 boxes. (Box 25-29)
  - Edna Hodges Correspondence (Taylor Family). (Box 26, Folder 18)
  - Harold Horton Correspondence. (Box 26, Folder 19)
  - Josephine Horton Correspondence (Chamblee-Horton Family). (Box 26, Folder 20)
  - Sue Horton Correspondence (Chamblee-Horton-Peebles Family). (Box 26, Folder 21)
  - William Horton Correspondence. (Box 26, Folder 22)
  - Shirla Howard Correspondence (Goodson-Stapp Family). (Box 26, Folder 23)
  - Dan Scarborough Hoyle Correspondence. (Box 26, Folder 24)
  - Ophelia Jacobs Correspondence (Pleasant Hill Cemetery, Greene County, Alabama). (Box 26, Folder 25)
  - Joan Carol Johnson Correspondence. (Box 26, Folder 26)
  - Jean Jordan Correspondence (Beachboard-Black-Smith-Walters Family). (Box 26, Folder 27)
  - Kay Cockrell Kazmir Correspondence (Cockrell Family). (Box 27, Folder 1)
  - Jack Keller Correspondence (David-Keller Family). (Box 27, Folder 2)
  - Cassandra Kite Correspondence (Gilbert Family). (Box 27, Folder 3)
  - Bill King Correspondence. (Box 27, Folder 4)
  - Joe David King Correspondence. (Box 27, Folder 5)
  - Peggy Bright King Correspondence (Lundy Family). (Box 27, Folder 6)
  - Susan Edith Smith King Correspondence. (Box 27, Folder 7)
  - Jim Knight Correspondence (Beachboard Family). (Box 27, Folder 8)
  - Leona Kitchen Lavender Correspondence (Goodson Family). (Box 27, Folder 9)
  - Onie King Leath Correspondence. (Box 27, Folder 10)
  - Doris Lester Correspondence (Rudy-Williams Family). (Box 27, Folder 11)
  - Martha Ann Lewter Correspondence. (Box 27, Folder 12)
  - Mary Marcy Correspondence (Tallent Family). (Box 27, Folder 13)
  - Donna Marr Correspondence (Davis-Campbell Family). (Box 27, Folder 14)
  - Vivian Marrs Correspondence (Patrick-Locker Family). (Box 27, Folder 14)
  - Audrene Davis Mathes Correspondence (Davis Family). (Box 27, Folder 15)
  - William R. Matsler Correspondence (Smith Family). (Box 27, Folder 16)
  - Belle Maxey Correspondence. (Box 27, Folder 17)
  - Jeraldine McDaniel Correspondence. (Box 27, Folder 18)
  - Elva McDougal Correspondence (Neal-Campbell Family). (Box 27, Folder 19)
  - F. B. McFee Correspondence. (Box 27, Folder 20)
  - Lillie McGee Correspondence (Davis Family). (Box 27, Folder 21)
  - Scott and Sue McKenzie Correspondence (Tallent Family). (Box 27, Folder 22)
  - Sarah Tallent McMurtrie Correspondence. (Box 27, Folder 23)
  - Brian McNeil Correspondence (Horton Family). (Box 27, Folder 24)
  - Alfred S. Miller, Jr., Correspondence (King Family). (Box 27, Folder 25)
  - Charles Monday Correspondence (Smith-Koonce-Dodson Family). (Box 27, Folder 26)
  - Franklin D. and Pattie Mosely Correspondence (King Family). (Box 27, Folder 27)
  - Adele Mullins Correspondence (King Family). (Box 27, Folder 28)
  - Mary Jane Murray Correspondence (Tallent Family). (Box 27, Folder 29)
  - Linda Myers Correspondence (Beachboard Family). (Box 27, Folder 30)
  - Jack and Leah Olsen Correspondence (Cockrell Family). (Box 27, Folder 31)
  - Jim Peebles Correspondence (McAfee Family). (Box 27, Folder 32)
  - Jackie Perkins Correspondence (Horton Family). (Box 27, Folder 33)
  - Jim Petersen Correspondence (Beachboard-Smith Family). (Box 27, Folder 34)
  - Eugene R. Perry Correspondence (Horton Family). (Box 27, Folder 35)
  - Dorothy Pruett Correspondence (Walters Family). (Box 27, Folder 36)
  - Phyllis Ratjen Correspondence (Black-Walters Family). (Box 28, Folder 1)
  - Susan Ray Correspondence (Horton Family). (Box 28, Folder 2)
  - Laverna Raymond Correspondence (Smith Family). (Box 28, Folder 3)
  - Hanna Reuber Correspondence. (Box 28, Folder 4)
  - Morton Rose, Jr., Correspondence (Beachboard Family). (Box 28, Folder 5)
  - Eleanor Earle King Russo Correspondence. (Box 28, Folder 6)
  - Penny San Marco Correspondence (Stamps Family). (Box 28, Folder 7)
  - Mary Etta Clark Simmons Correspondence. (Box 28, Folder 8)
  - Mary R. Simmons Correspondence (Roy Tallent Family). (Box 28, Folder 9)
  - Deena Smith Correspondence (Peebles-Hamlin Family). (Box 28, Folder 10)
  - James Jim Smith Correspondence. (Box 28, Folder 11)
  - Mike Smith Correspondence (Winstead Family). (Box 28, Folder 12)
  - Robert and Edna Smith Correspondence. (Box 28, Folder 13)
  - Smith Family of Friona, Texas (Smith-Brand Family). (Box 28, Folder 14)
  - Will Stamps Correspondence. (Box 28, Folder 15)
  - Maxine Stedham Correspondence (Tallent Family). (Box 28, Folder 16)
  - Loraine Dodson Story Correspondence. (Box 28, Folder 17)
  - Leonard and Althia Tallent Correspondence. (Box 28, Folder 18)
  - Evelyn Taylor Correspondence (Beachboard-Smith-Stamps Family). (Box 28, Folder 19)
  - Ola Thornthwaite Correspondence (Davis Family). (Box 28, Folder 20)
  - Jane Tipton Correspondence (Goodson Family). (Box 28, Folder 21)
  - Larry Tucker Correspondence (Smith Family). (Box 28, Folder 22)
  - Elsie Denton Turner Correspondence. (Box 28, Folder 23)
  - Robbie Turner Correspondence (McDaniel-Locker Family). (Box 28, Folder 24)
  - Bess Twaddle Correspondence (Gilbert Family). (Box 28, Folder 25)
  - Virgil L. Walker Correspondence (Walters-Cawthon Family). (Box 29, Folder 1)
  - Carolyn Walter Correspondence. (Box 29, Folder 2)
  - Roy Jones Walters Correspondence. (Box 29, Folder 3)
  - Myra Hester Warren Correspondence. (Box 29, Folder 4)
  - Eulalia Wellden Correspondence. (Box 29, Folder 5)
  - Frances Blanton Wetzel Correspondence (McAfee Family). (Box 29, Folder 6)
  - Cullum Wilson Correspondence (Caleb B. Smith Family). (Box 29, Folder 7)
  - Lillian Henderson Wilson Correspondence. (Box 29, Folder 8)
  - Irene Wingo Correspondence (Hollingsworth-Cockrell Family). (Box 29, Folder 9)
  - Joan Winstead Correspondence. (Box 29, Folder 10)
  - Anne Yeager Correspondence (Goodson Family). (Box 29, Folder 11)
  - Betty Young Correspondence (Dodson Family). (Box 29, Folder 12)
  - Nedra Yucker Correspondence (Rogers Family). (Box 29, Folder 13)
  - Correspondence, chronological, 1945. (Box 29, Folder 14)
  - Correspondence, chronological, 1976, 1979. (Box 29, Folder 15)
  - Correspondence, chronological, 1980-1983. (Box 29, Folder 16)
  - Correspondence, chronological, 1984-1985. (Box 29, Folder 17)
  - Correspondence, chronological, 1986-1989. (Box 29, Folder 18)
  - Correspondence, chronological,. (Box 29, Folder 19)
  - Correspondence, chronological, 1996-1997. (Box 29, Folder 20)
  - Correspondence, chronological, 1998-1999. (Box 29, Folder 21)
  - Correspondence, chronological, 2000-2003. (Box 29, Folder 22)
  - Correspondence, chronological, no date. (Box 29, Folder 23)
- Series III: Miscellaneous Genealogical Material., Extent: 3 boxes. (Box 30-32)
  Series III: Miscellaneous Genealogical Material consists of abstracts, applications, bibliographies, biographies, birth records, books, bulletins, clippings, correspondence, death records, deeds, forms, journals, judicial records, maps, marriage records, newspapers, notes, photographs, poems, and stationary used by Mary Josephine King in her genealogical research. Research materials cover Virginia, Alabama, Maryland, North Carolina, South Carolina, and Tennessee, and includes information on churches in North and South Carolina, on Albemarle Parish in Virginia, and on Beech Grove Cemetery in Tennessee. Information, applications, and forms concern several genealogical societies, including the Blount County Genealogical and Historical Society, the Daughters of the American Revolution, and the United Daughters of the Confederacy.
  - The Accokeek Creek Site: A Middle Atlantic Seaboard Culture Sequence. (Box 30)
  - Alabama: Portrait of a State. (Box 30)
  - Births, Deaths, and Sponsors, 1717-1778, from the Albemarle Parish Register of Surry and Sussex Counties, Virginia, also called Albemarle Parish Register: Births and Deaths. (Box 30)
  - Blount County, Tennessee, Deeds: Deed Book I, 1795-1819. (Box 30)
  - Genealogy Vocabulary Aids. (Box 30)
  - Handy Book for Genealogists. (Box 30)
  - Heath Springs South Carolina, 1752-1970. (Box 30)
  - Quaker Records. (Box 30)
  - Sims Settlement: Our Squatter Ancestors, 1806-1818. (Box 30)
  - The Blount Journal, volume I, numbers 1 and 2; volume II, number 2, 1985-1986. (Box 31, Folder 1)
  - Family Puzzler, 1990-1991. (Box 31, Folder 2)
  - Kelso Homecoming '86 Celebration. (Box 31, Folder 3)
  - Virginia Tidewater Genealogy, volume 13, number 2, June 1982. (Box 31, Folder 4)
  - Edenton Gazette and North Carolina General Advertiser, (transcript). (Box 31, Folder 5)
  - Elk Valley Times and Observer and Elk Valley Times, 1983-2003. (Box 31, Folder 6)
  - Your Community Shopper (Ardmore, Tennessee), 1979-2003. (Box 31, Folder 7)
  - Virginia newspapers, Hopewell News, Daily Press, Virginian-Pilot, 1976-1999. (Box 31, Folder 8)
  - Newspapers. (Box 31, Folder 9)
  - Clippings, various newspapers, 1983-1989. (Box 31, Folder 10)
  - Clippings, dated, no title, 1984-2003. (Box 31, Folder 11)
  - Clippings, no date, no title. (Box 31, Folder 12)
  - Map of medieval England and of Britain. (Box 31, Folder 13)
  - Franklin County, Tennessee, map. (Box 31, Folder 14)
  - Maps of Louisiana parishes, North Carolina and South Carolina counties. (Box 31, Folder 15)
  - Poem, A Little Mixed Up. (Box 31, Folder 16)
  - Births and Deaths from the Albemarle Parish Register. (Box 31, Folder 17)
  - Cavaliers and Pioneers excerpts. (Box 31, Folder 18)
  - Christ Presbyterian Church (Charlotte, North Carolina). (Box 31, Folder 19)
  - Col. Norwood's Voyage to Virginia. (Box 31, Folder 20)
  - George Washington Davis biographical sketch. (Box 31, Folder 21)
  - Everton's Genealogical Helper excerpt, May-June 1986. (Box 31, Folder 22)
  - Excerpts from The Messenger, August-September 1995. (Box 31, Folder 23)
  - Hanging Rock Methodist Church (Lancaster County, South Carolina). (Box 31, Folder 24)
  - Hawkins County, Tennessee wills from Tennessee Ancestors, volume 6, number 1, April 1990. (Box 31, Folder 25)
  - Hephziba Missionary Baptist Church (Wake County, North Carolina). (Box 31, Folder 26)
  - Excerpts from History of Blount County (Tennessee). (Box 31, Folder 27)
  - Kershaw District, South Carolina, Census, 1840. (Box 31, Folder 28)
  - A Master Plan for North Carolina Research from National Genealogical Society Quarterly. (Box 31, Folder 29)
  - Naming patters and family relationships. (Box 31, Folder 30)
  - Perquimans County, North Carolina, history. (Box 31, Folder 31)
  - Shiloh Baptist Church (Camden County, North Carolina). (Box 31, Folder 32)
  - A Short History of Jamestown. (Box 31, Folder 33)
  - Some Notes on Research in East Tennessee from Heritage Quest. (Box 31, Folder 34)
  - Tracing Your Family Tree from Better Homes and Gardens. (Box 31, Folder 35)
  - Order forms for Virginia Marriages. (Box 31, Folder 36)
  - Bibliographies of Jamestown 350th anniversary historical booklets and for Bicentennial booklets. (Box 31, Folder 37)
  - Jury list, Pasquotank County, North Carolina, 1723. (Box 31, Folder 38)
  - Wake County, North Carolina, court minutes, 1794. (Box 31, Folder 39)
  - Currituck County, North Carolina, record of deeds, 1763-1764. (Box 31, Folder 40)
  - Tennesseans in the Civil War. (Box 31, Folder 41)
  - Roster, 4th Tennessee Cavalry, Company E. (Box 31, Folder 42)
  - Blount County Genealogical and Historical Society membership list. (Box 32, Folder 1)
  - Daughters of the American Revolution-North Carolina Chapter. (Box 32, Folder 2)
  - Lincoln County Genealogical Society (Tennessee). (Box 32, Folder 3)
  - National Genealogical Society. (Box 32, Folder 4)
  - NCGS News: Newsletter of the North Carolina Genealogical Society. (Box 32, Folder 5)
  - Tidewater Genealogical Society-20th anniversary seminar. (Box 32, Folder 6)
  - United Daughters of the Confederacy-Stonewall Chapter, Portsmouth, Virginia. (Box 32, Folder 7)
  - Virginia Beach Genealogical Society. (Box 32, Folder 8)
  - Wake County Genealogical Society. (Box 32, Folder 9)
  - National Genealogical Society forms. (Box 32, Folder 10)
  - Daughters of the American Revolution applications-filled. (Box 32, Folder 11)
  - United Daughters of the Confederacy forms-Mary Josephine King and Susan Edith Smith King. (Box 32, Folder 12)
  - Flagon and Trencher: Descendants of Colonial Tavern Keepers. (Box 32, Folder 13)
  - Census forms-blank. (Box 32, Folder 14)
  - Virginia Tidewater Genealogy forms and Tidewater Genealogical Society receipt. (Box 32, Folder 15)
  - National Archives veterans records form (blank and filled). (Box 32, Folder 16)
  - Catalogs and order forms. (Box 32, Folder 17)
  - Monthly schedule sheets (blank). (Box 32, Folder 18)
  - Death certificate request forms. (Box 32, Folder 19)
  - United Daughters of the Confederacy forms (blank). (Box 32, Folder 20)
  - Genealogy research forms. (Box 32, Folder 21)
  - Genealogy help forms. (Box 32, Folder 22)
  - Portsmouth General Hospital stationary. (Box 32, Folder 23)
  - Genealogy course notes-ODU. (Box 32, Folder 24)
  - Seminar materials. (Box 32, Folder 25)
  - Miscellaneous genealogical notes., folder 1 of 3 (Box 32, Folder 26)
  - Miscellaneous genealogical notes., folder 2 of 3 (Box 32, Folder 27)
  - Miscellaneous genealogical notes., folder 3 of 3 (Box 32, Folder 28)
  - Unidentified photographs-couples. (Box 32, Folder 29)
  - Unidentified photographs-families. (Box 32, Folder 30)
  - Unidentified photographs-mulitple individuals. (Box 32, Folder 31)
  - Unidentified photographs-women. (Box 32, Folder 32)
  - Unidentified photographs-men. (Box 32, Folder 33)
  - Unidentified photographs-children. (Box 32, Folder 34)
  - Unidentified photographs-Confederate cemetery, Beech Grove, Tennessee. (Box 32, Folder 35)
- Series IV: Personal Papers., Extent: 4 boxes. (Box 33-36)
  Series IV: Personal Papers contains autograph books, certificates, pamphlets, photographs, plaques, programs, and yearbooks detailing Mary Josephine King's junior high and high school education; her nursing education and career as a nursing instructor at schools and hospitals in Mississippi, West Virginia, and Virginia, including Portsmouth General Hospital. Also includes certificates for classes taken for personal interest, for her hobbies, and for membership in the National Genealogical Society. Also includes a pamphlet on Zuma Memorial Hospital in Nigeria.
  - Nursing registration certificate, Mississippi, 1949. (Box 33, Folder 1)
  - Nursing registration certificates, North Carolina, 1945. (Box 33, Folder 2)
  - Nursing registration certificate, license, Virginia, 1958, 1988. (Box 33, Folder 3)
  - Nursing registration certificate, West Virginia, 1951. (Box 33, Folder 4)
  - Chicago Lying-in Hospital and Dispensery nursing course certificate, 1948. (Box 33, Folder 5)
  - Eastern Virginia Medical Authority nursing courses, 1977-1982. (Box 33, Folder 6)
  - Georgetown University nursing course certificate, 1982. (Box 33, Folder 7)
  - Hampton Institute nursing course certificate, 1976. (Box 33, Folder 8)
  - National Institute for Nursing nursing courses certificates, 1974-1978. (Box 33, Folder 9)
  - Naval Regional Medical Center nursing course certificate, 1982. (Box 33, Folder 10)
  - Norfolk Public Schools nursing course certificate, 1976. (Box 33, Folder 11)
  - Old Dominion University nursing courses certificates, 1978-1981. (Box 33, Folder 12)
  - Tidewater Community College nursing course certificate, 1977. (Box 33, Folder 13)
  - University of North Carolina nursing courses certificates, 1966-1968. (Box 33, Folder 14)
  - Virginia Commonwealth University nursing course certificate, 1977. (Box 33, Folder 15)
  - Photograph of nursing class [at Louise Obici School of Nursing?], 1992[?]. (Box 33, Folder 16)
  - Hobby Industry of America certificates, 1975-1976. (Box 33, Folder 17)
  - National Genealogical Society certificate, 1978. (Box 33, Folder 18)
  - ODU-Climbing your family tree certificate, 1976. (Box 33, Folder 19)
  - Tidewater Community College personal interest courses certificates, 1974-1977. (Box 33, Folder 20)
  - United States Air Force certificate, 1971. (Box 33, Folder 21)
  - Autograph book, 1936-1937. (Box 33)
  - Autograph book, 1941. (Box 33)
  - Retirement award and commencement announcement for the Louise Obici School of Nursing, 1992. (Box 33)
  - Photographs of Mary Josephine King. (Box 33)
  - Signing Off, Alexander Graham Junior High School (Charlotte, North Carolina) yearbook, 1937. (Box 34)
  - Signing Off, Alexander Graham Junior High School (Charlotte, North Carolina) yearbook, 1938. (Box 34)
  - Snips and Cuts, Central High School (Charlotte, North Carolina) yearbook, 1941. (Box 34)
  - Snips and Cuts, Central High School (Charlotte, North Carolina) yearbook, 1942. (Box 34)
  - Central High School, Charlotte, North Carolina, class reunion, 1982. (Box 34)
  - Central High School, Charlotte, North Carolina, class reunion, 1992. (Box 34)
  - Crisp 'n Curls, Presbyterian Hospital School of Nursing (Charlotte, North Carolina) yearbook, 1945. (Box 34)
  - The Chart, The School of Nursing of Mississippi Baptist Hospital (Jackson, Mississippi) yearbook, 1951. (Box 34)
  - Bulletin of Monongalia General Hospital School of Nursing. (Box 34)
  - The Lamp, Portsmouth General Hospital School of Nursing (Portsmouth, Virginia) yearbook, 1959. (Box 35)
  - The Lamp, Portsmouth General Hospital School of Nursing (Portsmouth, Virginia) yearbook, 1960. (Box 35)
  - The Lamp, Portsmouth General Hospital School of Nursing (Portsmouth, Virginia) yearbook, 1964. (Box 35)
  - The Lamp, Portsmouth General Hospital School of Nursing (Portsmouth, Virginia) yearbook, 1965. (Box 35)
  - The Lamp, Portsmouth General Hospital School of Nursing (Portsmouth, Virginia) yearbook, 1966. (Box 35)
  - The Lamp, Portsmouth General Hospital School of Nursing (Portsmouth, Virginia) yearbook, 1966. (Box 35)
  - The Lamp, Portsmouth General Hospital School of Nursing (Portsmouth, Virginia) yearbook, 1967. (Box 35)
  - The Lamp, Portsmouth General Hospital School of Nursing (Portsmouth, Virginia) yearbook, 1969. (Box 35)
  - The Lamp, Portsmouth General Hospital School of Nursing (Portsmouth, Virginia) yearbook, 1970. (Box 36)
  - The Lamp, Portsmouth General Hospital School of Nursing (Portsmouth, Virginia) yearbook, 1970. (Box 36)
  - The Lamp, Portsmouth General Hospital School of Nursing (Portsmouth, Virginia) yearbook, 1971. (Box 36)
  - The Lamp, Portsmouth General Hospital School of Nursing (Portsmouth, Virginia) yearbook, 1972. (Box 36)
  - The Lamp, Portsmouth General Hospital School of Nursing (Portsmouth, Virginia) yearbook, 1973. (Box 36)
  - The Special Progress Report of Louise Obici School of Nursing,1990. (Box 36)
  - Zuma Memorial Hospital (Nigeria), 1965[?]. (Box 36, Folder 1)
  - The PGH Artery (Portsmouth General Hospital), June 1974. (Box 36, Folder 2)
  - Old Dominion University commencement, 1974. (Box 36, Folder 3)
- Series V: Oversize., Extent: 2 boxes and 1 item. (Box 37-38)
  Series V: Oversize contains photographs of Mary Josephine King, her nursing school class, and others; diplomas from Central High School (Birmingham, Alabama), Central High School (Charlotte, North Carolina), Presbyterian Hospital School of Nursing, Queens College, and Old Dominion University; marriage certificates, and a commencement announcement. Also includes Girl Scout sash and hat, graduation cap, scout cards, and Girl Scout badge certificates. Also contains a copy of enlistments in the United States Army prior to May 1815 (letter K) and a Virginia auditor's account from 1783.
  - Girl Scout hat and sash. (Box 37)
  - Graduation cap and hood. (Box 37)
  - Photograph of Annie Florence Goodson Chamblee. (Box 37)
  - Marriage certificate, Greene County, Alabama, for Berry King and Molly Horton, 1828. (Box 37)
  - Marriage certificate, Greene County, Alabama, for Wheaton Williams and Aquila W. Cockrell, 1838. (Box 37)
  - Marriage certificate, Greene County, Alabama, for Berry S. King and Sarah F. Williams, 1859. (Box 37)
  - Enlistments in the United States Army prior to 1815 (letter K). (Box 37)
  - Auditor's account, 1783. (Box 37)
  - Girl Scout badge certificates and Red Cross life saving certificate. (Box 37)
  - Photograph, Mary Josephine King. (Box 37)
  - Photograph, Presbyterian Hospital School of Nursing class, 1945. (Box 37)
  - Diploma, Central High School (Charlotte, North Carolina), 1942. (Box 37)
  - Marriage license, Jefferson County, Alabama, for John Berry King and Sue Edith Smith, 1923. (Box 37)
  - Certificate, Dale Carnegie course on Effective Speaking and Human Relations, 1975. (Box 37)
  - Photograph, Mary Josephine King. (Box 38)
  - Diploma, Presbyterian Hospital School of Nursing (Charlotte, North Carolina), 1945. (Box 38)
  - Diploma, Queens College (Charlotte, North Carolina), 1947. (Box 38)
  - Commencement announcement, Old Dominion University, 1974. (Box 38)
  - Diploma, Old Dominion University, 1974. (Box 38)
  - Photographic portrait, Mary Josephine King, 1947. (Box 38)
  - Diploma, Central High School (Birmingham, Alabama) for Sue Edith Smith, 1918. (Box 38)
  - Photographic portrait of Mary Josephine King (Girl Scout, graduate, nurse).